

🛘 +447856417121 | 🗷 seanababio3@gmail.com | 🏕 babstah.github.io/web-portfolio/ | 🖸 babstah | 🛅 sean-ababio

Summary ___

A front-end developer who is highly motivated and experienced with considerable industry knowledge gained through creating dynamic web applications for numerous clients and as part of online course projects. I am proficient of organising, producing and debugging a variety of webbased applications that use an assortment of technologies. Aiming to flourish as a front-end developer by fusing a broad educational background with solid creative expertise.

Work Experience _____

Freelance Web Developer

United Kingdom, Remote

May 2022 - Current

- · Engineered scalable, responsive, multi-platform and SEO friendly websites for multiple clients using HTML5, CSS3 +BEM, JavaScript ES6+ and React best practises
- Included SEO, responsive, multi-platform and hosting support, enabling their website to be used by any browser or device.
- Improved website performance by compression, caching and lazy loading images and components.
- · Collaborating with clients to understand their needs and requirements for their web development projects.

Frontend Simplified Online Bootcamp

FRONTEND DEVELOPER INTERN

Jul. 2022 - Dec. 2022

- · Transformed a completely static HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React single page application into an interactive user interface using animations, transitions and carousels.
- Utilized Git version control and the GitHub interface to work and thrive in a collaborative team environment.
- Replicated UI and UX designs and reviewed code through weekly code reviews
- · Processed API requests to dynamically represent data from a cloud server and represented it through skeleton loading states, pagination and dynamic routing

Frontend Simplified Online Bootcamp

FRONTEND DEVELOPER SUPPORT

Sep. 2022 - current

- Supported 1,000+ students using HTML, CSS, Flexbox, JavaScript and React best practices
- Utilized debugging best practices using Google Chrome inspect element tooling.
- · Simplified difficult programming concepts including responsive website development, CSS layout, Promises and API requests.
- Built Scalable Landing pages, and websites using advanced languages and practices

Skills

.HTML,

.css,

.Javascript.

.VanillaJS,

.React,

.TailwindCSS,

.APIs,

.Typescript,

.Git.

.Redux,

Projects

ChatGPT Clone

- The project aims to create a chatbot that can converse in a human-like way
- React is used for building the user interface and ensuring a smooth user experience
- GPT-3 model API is integrated with the chatbot to generate responses
- JavaScript is used to handle the conversation's logic and flow.

Weather API Application

- Fully functional weather app using React JS framework
- The app can display real-time weather forecast for any city or country in the world
- · The user can input the location they want to check for the weather
- · Used axios to connect with the API

Modern Banking App Website

- A website was built using JavaScript, Typescript, React, and TailwindCSS
- · The website has a stunning hero section, high-quality assets and gradients, business stats, and testimonials
- The website is responsive, which means it can be viewed on all devices
- The feature sections of the website are reusable and have call-to-action buttons

Halloween E-Commerce Store

- HTML, CSS, and Vanilla JavaScript were used to create the website
- The website features a responsive header and navbar
- Swiper.js was used to create a responsive slider effect.
- The navbar has a toggle effect.

Snake Game

- The game is created using JavaScript, HTML, and CSS
- Best practices for game development are displayed.

Food Restaurant Website

- Developed a responsive food restaurant website with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Added a pizza loading animation with a fadeout effect using JavaScript.
- Created a navbar with a toggle menu bar effect.

Educational Course Website

- Developed a multi-page educational website using HTML, CSS, and Vanilla JavaScript.
- The website is responsive and uses a navbar with a toggle menu bar effect.
- Flexbox was used throughout the website to ensure responsiveness on different devices.

Education

Harvard University

Cambridge, USA

CS50 INTRODUCTION TO COMPUTER SCIENCE (ONLINE)

 Harvard CS50 Introduction to Computer Science is an online and on-campus course that provides an introduction to the fundamental concepts of computer science and programming. The course covers a range of topics, including algorithms, data structures, programming languages, web development, and computer science theory.

Madeley Academy Telford, United Kingdom

GCSES AND BTECS

- BTEC IT D
- BTEC Business D*
- BTEC Applied Science D
- English 6
- Mathematics 7
- · Combined Science 5 and 4
- · Geography 6
- · BTEC Health and Social Care L2P
- BTFC Creative Media L2M

Sep 2015 - Aug 2022